Satishkumar N. Purswani

Technical Lead II Location: Mumbai

Profile and Career Objective

Passionate Software Engineer with more than 9years of professional experience in building web applications using variety of architectures.

Looking for competitive and challenging job, which will be beneficial to both, the organization and myself by speedy implementation of professional knowledge and experience into actions where I can prove my technical and functional expertise and work towards the growth of the organization.

Employment Details

<u>CitiusTech Healthcare Technologies Pvt. Ltd. – Sept., 2018 – till Date</u>

1. Designing, managing and implementing solutions for the one of the biggest clients of CitiusTech – Kidney Dialysis.

Managing team for backend, handling and guiding new members in the team, involved in thorough knowledge transfers.

Decision making and having end to end discussion of the features related to application with stakeholders.

2. Developing new interfaces, suggesting solutions, designing and making enhancements to existing application that is being used by the hospital staff to handle communication between doctors, nurses and other healthcare providers – similar to outlook but very much advanced to directly support imaging system.

Majesco Ltd.- Jan.2017 - Sept. 2018

- 1. P&C Insurance Suite consisting of 3modules Policy, Billing and Claims Product based.
- 2. Part of Claims Module to implementing solutions using Webservices.
- 3. Managed deployments, configured load balancer, toolkit upgrades etc.
- 4. Configured load balancer using Apache httpd2.4.
- 5. Developed integration module to connect with policy server.

Syntel Pvt. Ltd. (Currently known as Atos-Syntel) - Jul.,2012 – Jan. 2017

- 1. Developed and enhancements for insurance-based web application an open portal for customer and business.
- 2. Solution suggestion, development and integration of payment gateway for automatic credit card
- 3. Integration MuleSoft/Salesforce and many other modules independently.
- 4. Involved in development of synchronizing data in application with CRM (SALESFORCE/ MULESOFT).

Please find detailed information about projects/assignments undertaken on the next page of

Educational Qualifications

- MBA(EPGDBM) in Business Management from Symbiosis University, Pune (SCCE) 2021 Cleared with 7.52 GPA
- Master's Degree in Science specialization Information Technology, Majors Cloud Computing, Ethical Hacking. – 2016 – 5.0 CGPA
- Bachelor's Degree in Science specialization Information Technology 2012 62.19%
- **♦** HSC 2009 71%
- **❖** SSC − 2007 − 64%

Awards & Recognition

- Recognized as Ace team member for owning and managing 2 separate modules simultaneously
- Majesco Honour Award for streamlining packaging process.
- Awarded SYNTEL VALUES SPOT AWARD as Employee recognition for displaying values in contributing towards organization.

Hobbies, Passion and General Information

- YouTuber @ GodOfGizmos
- ❖ Passionate about new Technologies in the market
- Self-motivated employee who performs efficiently to accomplish business goals and the ability to learn new skills quickly and effectively.
- Strong communication and interpersonal skills backed by sound analytical, technical and leadership skills. A team player as well as a self-starter with the ability to manage multiple assignments.
- ❖ Satishkumar Purswani LinkedIn Profile Click Here

Details

EMAIL ADDRESS

PURSWANISUNNY1@GMAIL.COM

CONTACT NUMBER:

(+91) 9969497799 / (+91) 9326267799

NATIONALITY INDIAN

PAN

BYTPP8224P

DATE OF BIRTH 09/05/1991

PASSPORT NUMBER. T7994999

JShell

Primary Skills		
Name	Last Used	Self-Rating
Microservices	Present	****
Core Java	Present	****
Java 8	Present	****
Java	Present	****
Spring Boot	Present	****
Spring Web Flux	Present	****
Spring Integration	Present	****
Spring Batch	Present	
REST Webservices	Present	****
GIT	Present	
Apache Kafka	Present	
Junits	Present	
Mockito	Present	
Apache POI Lib	2018	

2018

Google Cloud Platfo				
KubernetesEngine	Present	****		
Spanner-DB.	Present	***		
<u>Database Technologies</u>				
Cassandra	Present	****		
POSTgres	2020	★★★☆☆		
MS-SQL	2020	****		
Oracle 11g	2017	**************************************		

Ordere 11g	2017	
Messaging Servic		
Apache Kafka	Present	****

Other Tools

Jenkins	Present	****
Maven	Present	★★★☆
SVN	2018	****
HTML/CSS	2018	****
JavaScript	2013	
Docker	2020	
Jira	Present	
Confluence	Present	
Rally	2020	
Notepad++	Present	
-	l	

<u>CitiusTech Healthcare Technologies Pvt. Ltd. – Sept., 2018 – till Date</u>

Client Name: Confidential

 $\underline{\text{Domain:}} \ \text{Healthcare} - \text{Kidney Dialysis}$

<u>Duration: Dec, 2019 – Till Date</u>

<u>Technologies Used:</u> Core Java, Java 8 – (Streams, Lambda, Optional, Functional Programming etc.), Spring Framework, Spring Boot, Spring Batch, Spring Integration, Spring Web flux, J2EE, Microservices, Webservices, Java Collections, Java concurrency, multi-threading, Apache Cassandra, Google Spanner, Apache Kafka, Kibana, Dynatrace, Agile Methodology based project, GIT.

<u>Overview about the project –</u> Every single detail in the click was captured in pen and paper mode, all the vitals' calculations were carried out manually. Nurses and doctors were having tough time to manage these things.

This application automated all the process, calculations in real time. Now doctors, nurses and physicians can actually focus on the job instead making all other chaos work.

Roles and Responsibilities -

- 1) Requirement gathering, Walk through sessions from the BAs, Feature clarifications, Part of Sprint Planning
- 2) Creating solutions, HLD/LLDs, Sequence diagrams, Application Flows, Reviewing PRs for code quality Technical grooming
- 3) Implementing features end to end Individual contributor
- 4) Interviewing candidate for the open position for the project as well as for the organization
- 5) Over all understanding of the functional and technical requirements of the application
- 6) Guiding, helping, delegating responsibilities about the task to new team members.
- 7) Managing team members for the technical walkthrough and guiding team leading role.
- 8) Discussion with client and onsite team members about the requirements, implementation and changes required in the current code base.
- 9) Implementing POCs, creating design documents.

Client Name: Confidential

Domain: Healthcare - Hospital Communications and Management

Duration: Sept., 2018 - Dec., 2019

<u>Technologies Used:</u> Core Java, Java 8 – (Streams, Lambda, Optional, Functional Programming etc.), Spring Framework, Spring Boot, Spring Batch, Spring Integration, Spring Web flux, J2EE, Microservices, Webservices, Java Collections, Java concurrency, multi-threading, MS-SQL, Apache POI, JShell, Agile Methodology based project, GIT.

Overview about the project – This web-based application was deployed inside the hospital premises on the private cloud environment. This used to capture all the patient demographics, directly used to communicate with RIS, DICOM and other imaging devices. Physicians, Doctors, Practitioners were used to directly connect to cloud architecture to get the information of patient. Mark, edit, update and share it with other hospital staff using this application.

Roles and Responsibilities -

- 1) Requirement clarification, creating user stories for self and team members Sprint Planning
- 2) Discussing the HLD/LLDs including implementation with the solution architects Technical grooming
- 3) Guiding team members about the application and the implementation of the HLD/LLDs
- 4) Implementing solutions, taking active roles in the code reviews, suggestions.
- 5) Created architecture to read the data from application into excel sheet and migrate to another database.
- 6) Migrated case (form of message) attachments to different structure using JShell.
- 7) Worked as a full stack developer with hands on experience in Angular1.x, HTML, CSS.
- 8) Quick RCA of the bugfix, suggestions to fix and implementations
- 9) Maintained code quality by doing PR reviews and Junits.
- 10) Technical walkthroughs and demos for clients and internal stakeholders, Interviewing candidates for the open position in the organization.

Majesco Ltd.- Jan.2017 – Sept. 2018

<u>Client Name:</u> Product Based Organization – Policy Suite

Domain: Insurance P&C

<u>Duration: Jan.2017 – Sept. 2018</u>

<u>Technologies Used:</u> Core Java, Java Collections, Webservices, Spring, Oracle 11g, HTML, CSS, SVN. Agile Methodology based project.

<u>Overview about the project –</u> There is a product suite of Majesco around Insurance domain which includes Policy, Billing and Claims. I was part of Claims module. All the modules used to communicate using webservices.

Roles and Responsibilities -

- 1) Designing & Implementing User Stories on ICD ICM Proprietary tool which is based on Java Technology.
- 2) Cleared Insurance P&C L1 internal certification from Majesco.
- 3) Managing deployments, Toolkit upgrades, packaging and deployment issues.
- 4) Configured load balancer using Apache httpd2.4
- 5) Developed integration modules to connect with policy server.
- 6) Handled and streamlined release packing process.
- 7) Important key player to communicate with other teams related to cross functional features.

<u> Atos Syntel Pvt. Ltd. (Syntel) - Jul.,2012 – Jan. 2017</u>

<u>Client Name:</u> Confidential <u>Domain:</u> Insurance - Auto Duration: Jun. 2015 – Jan. 2017

<u>Technologies Used:</u> JSPs, Servlets, Core Java, Java Collections, Multi-threading, EJBs, Sun Application Server, GlassFish 2.1, MS-SQL, MuleSoft, External APIs to get quotes, HTML, CSS, Plain JavaScript, SVN, GIT., Agile Methodology based project

Overview about the project: Syntel was having contract to enhance and develop the features of insurance-based project. This application was used by insurance agents to share the Insurance quotes and get the policies registered. This client was Canada based and we used to implement new feature Roles and Responsibilities:

- 1) Worked on new enhancements based on MVC architecture and develop controller and models for the new requirements.
- 2) JSF models designed for new enhancement with respective impacting modules based on new User Story constraints.
- 3) Involved in development of new Module "Coverage Endorsement" based on Java Data Mapping and JS functionality.
- 4) Developed payment gateway integration module independently.
- 5) Developed deep-link/salesforce entry point module for the web-based application.
- 6) Involved in development of synchronization of data in our application with CRM(SALESFORCE/ MULESOFT)
- 7) Involved in environment setup on development & QA. Server.

<u>Client Name:</u> Confidential <u>Domain:</u> Insurance - Auto

<u>Duration: Aug., 2012 – Jun.2015</u>

<u>Technologies Used:</u> JSPs, Servlets, Core Java, Java Collections, Multi-threading, EJBs, Sun Application Server, GlassFish 2.1, MS-SQL, MuleSoft, External APIs to get quotes, HTML, CSS, Plain JavaScript, SVN, GIT., Waterfall model.

Overview about the project: Syntel was having contract to enhance and develop the features of insurance-based project. This application was used by insurance agents as well as there was open portal for the public to get the quote from the internet-based website. Open portal web application user interface was in Chinese language.

Roles and Responsibilities:

- 1) Experience in developing controller and models for the new requirements.
- 2) Involved in development of new flow of the application.
- 3) Involved in enhancement of module to get premiums for the engine on client side.
- 4) Involved in development of UI Controllers Model (Bean classes) workflow as per the SRS.
- 5) Developed new module context and design the impacting modules for effective workflow.
- 6) Developed JAVA bean classes for module context and configure the backend functionality to get response.
- 7) Consuming, Designing and Execution of Web Services for Module.